(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T13:37:02.475004",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
「もう、どうやったって無駄かもな」
"No matter what I do, it's probably useless,"
泣きそうな顔を見ていた
watching your tearful face.
「諦めないでよ」みたいな
Words like "Don't give up"
言葉じゃ全然足りない！
are definitely not enough!
「そしたらもっと元気を出さなきゃ、
"Then you've got to cheer up more,
明日も眩んじゃう！」って
or tomorrow will be dazzled too!"
君を連れ出していく
I pull you along
無理矢理かなァ
maybe a bit forcefully.
陽射しにブルーになる
Feeling blue in the sunlight,
君のことやっぱ正直心配だ
honestly, I'm worried about you.
瞳が潤っていく
Your eyes are getting watery.
「弱虫な僕には、ダメだよきっと…」
"A coward like me is probably hopeless..."
だけど信じる、君だから。
But I believe in you, because it's you.
真っすぐ前を向いて？
Look straight ahead, okay?
ホントにダメな時は、
When things are really tough,
君の心を支えてあげる
I'll support your heart.
「いっそ」なんて諦めじゃ
Giving up with a "might as well"
絶対ダメだからね
is definitely out of the question,
so absolutely don't do it—
一緒に進もう
let's move forward together!
独りぼっちを壊しちゃおう、ほら！
Let's shatter being all alone, come on!
「どうなっているんだか分からない」
"I don't even know what's going on,"
君はまだ泣きそうなんだ
you still look like you're about to cry.
溜息ばっかで目を瞑っちゃ
closing your eyes with nothing but sighs—
駄目置きばっかで目をつ
keeping your eyes shut tightly—
「もう、どうやったって無駄かもな」
"No matter what I do, it's useless anyway,"
泣きそうな顔 見ていた
I saw your almost crying face.
「諦めないでよ」みたいな
"Don't give up!"—words like that
言葉じゃ 全然足りない！
are nowhere near enough!
「そしたらもっと元気を出しなさい、
"Then I've got to cheer you up even more,
明日も眩しいわ！」って
or tomorrow will be dazzling!"
君を連れ出していく
I'm taking you out with me.
無理やりかな
It might be a bit forceful,
日差しにブルーになる
turning the sunlight blue.
君のことやっぱ正直心配だ
I'm genuinely worried about you.
瞳が潤っていく
Your eyes are welling up with tears.
「弱虫な僕には、だめだよきっと…」
"It's no good for a coward like me..."
だけど信じる、君だから。
But I believe in you, because it's you.
真っすぐ前を向いて？
Look straight ahead!
ホンマにダメな時は、
When things get really tough,
君の心を支えてあげる。
I'll support your heart.
「いっそ」なんて諦めぢゃ
"Let's not give up, that's strictly forbidden,
絶対ダメだから ねぇ、一緒に進もう？
hey, let's move forward together!"
「独りぼっち」を壊しちゃおう、ほら！
Let's shatter that loneliness, come on!
「どうなっているんだろ解らない」
"I have no idea what's going on."
君はまだ泣きそうだ
You still look like you're about to cry.
溜め息ばかりで 目を伏せちゃぅ
Just sighing and averting your eyes—
ほら、絶対絶命！
hey, this is a desperate situation!
「もっと頑張んなくちゃ 想いも
"I've got to try harder,
昨日になれいちゃう！」って
or my thoughts will vanish into yesterday!"
街を駆け出していく
I start running through the streets.
無理やりだね
It's a bit forced, isn't it?
夕暮れブルーになる
Dusk turns blue.
日差しが閉ざしている その一瞬で
In that moment when the sunlight closes off,
立ち待ち投げ出した顔
a face that stopped and looked down—
音もなく涙がこぼれて消えた
tears spilled silently and vanished.
ひどく小さなこの世界が
This terribly small world
大きく牙をむいて
shows its massive fangs,
君の心をうつむかせる
striking at your heart:
小さな言葉じゃ
"I wish we could have been together."
もう全然届かなくても
Even if small words no longer reach you at all,
力になりたい
I want to be your strength,
助けたいんだよ。叶えてよ、ねぇ！
I want to help you. Make it happen, hey!
信じる、君だから。
I believe in you, because it's you.
本気の声出して
Raise your voice in earnest!
絶対ダメなんかなじない！
It's definitely not impossible!
君が望めば、また出会える！
If you wish for it, we can meet again!
大きな深呼吸で
With a big, deep breath,
遠くのお月様に
facing the distant moon,
弱気な君が
the weak-hearted you shouted,
「やってやるっさ！」と
"I'm gonna do it!"
叫んでいた 少し格好いいかな、まぁ
Looking a little cool, right? Well...
どきどきどきしちゃってる
My heart is beating super fast,
こいつは全然気づかないな
and this guy isn't noticing at all.
本当はもっと話したいのに
Actually, I want to talk more with him,
しつこいなんて思われてもな
even if it seems like I'm being persistent.
授業中も上の空だし
My head is in the clouds during class,
こんなの悔しいけど仕方ないな
so frustrating, but I guess it can't be helped.
恋空予報 叶わないかも
The love sky forecast might not come true.
晴れのち曇りで雨が降るでしょう
Clear skies turning to clouds, then rain.
あいつの笑顔 いつも見とれて
I'm always charmed by that guy's smile—
私 本日 恋してる模様
today, it looks like I'm in love.
ほらほらもたもたしてると
Hey look, if I slow down just a bit,
あっという間にあいつは帰るぞ
that guy will go home in a flash!
「今までずっと言えなかったけど、
"I couldn't say it until now,
本当はずっと好きだったから」
but truly, I've always liked you!"
答えは待って！すぐに言わないで
"I'll wait for your answer! Don't say anything yet!"
耳を塞ぎたくて ただ怖くて
I want to block my ears, I'm just so scared.
恋空予報 叶えてお願いい
The love sky forecast, please grant my wish:
雨が降ってるけど 一緒に帰ろう
"It's raining, but let's go home together."
あいつの言葉 いつも思い出して
I'll always remember that guy's words.
私 明日も恋してる模様
Tomorrow too, it looks like I'm in love.
遠くにかかる虹 ふわり混ざる夕日
A rainbow spanning far and wide,
傘をたたんで手をつないだ 幸せもの
folding my umbrella to hold your hand, so happy.
今日も恋空予報 これからもきっと
The love sky forecast, today again, surely from here on—
晴れのち曇りで雨も降るでしょう
Clear skies turning to clouds, and rain too.
あいつの笑顔 いつも見とれて
I'm always charmed by his smile.
私 本日 恋してる模様
Today, it looks like I'm in love.
ほらほらもたもたしてると
Hey look, hesitation just makes time fly,
あっと言う間にあいつは帰るぞ
and all of a sudden, he's walking away!
今までずっと言えなかったけど
"I couldn't say it until now,
本当はずっと好きだったから
but truly, I've always liked you."
答えは待って すぐに言わないで
"I'll wait for your answer! Don't say anything yet!"
耳を塞ぎたくて ただ怖くて
I want to block my ears, I'm just so scared.
恋空予報 叶えてお願いい
The love sky forecast, please grant my wish:
雨が降ってるけど 一緒に帰ろう
"It's raining, but let's go home together."
あいつの言葉 いつも思い出して
I'll always remember those words,
私 明日も恋してる模様
always recalling them, wishing tomorrow...
遠くにかかる虹 ふわり混ざる夕日
A rainbow spanning far and wide,
傘をたたんで手をつないだ 幸せもの
folding my umbrella to hold your hand, so happy.
今日も恋空予報 これからもきっと
The love sky forecast, today again, surely from here on—
晴れのち曇りで雨も降るでしょう
Clear skies turning to clouds, and rain too.
あいつの笑顔 いつも見とれて
I'm always charmed by his smile.
私 本日 恋してる模様
Today, it looks like I'm in love.
明日も恋してる模様
Tomorrow too, I'll be in love,
今日も恋してる模様
just like this, forever.
いつも通りの笑顔を
The usual smile,
いつも見とれてて私
always admiring it, I
本日恋してる模様
seem to be in love today.
ずっとこのまま恋してたい私
I want to keep falling in love just like this,
このまま恋してたい私
keep loving you just like this.
みーんな完璧！完璧！完璧！完璧！
Everyone, perfect! Perfect! Perfect! Perfect!
このライブ生誕の、う、うさだ
This live, birthday... U-, Usada...
てか、てかよ、ほやほやほや
Wait, hey, hey, fresh, fresh, fresh—
見いてるぺこか、ありがとー！
Are you watching, peko? Thank you!
どうペコだった？
How was it, peko?
まずはお月見生やせると、恋空予報2曲やっちゃった！
First, with 'Otsukimi Hayaseru' and 'Koi-Sora Yohou,' we did two songs!
どうペコですか？可愛いぺこか？可愛いかった？
How was it, peko? Was it cute, peko? Was it cute?
ああうれしありがと！
Ah, I'm so happy, thank you!
今日は本当にね、うさだぺこーらの生誕祭ライブ来ていただき、まことにまことにありがとうございました！
Today, truly, thank you so much for coming to Usada Pekora's birthday live!
そして、あ、こっちか、こちらのね、ぜひ、うさだぺこら生誕祭で、あのたくさんね、つぶやいていただけたら嬉しいぺこだなあって思うぺこですので、どうぞどうぞどうぞたくさんつぶやいてほしいなと思うぺこです。
And, ah, over here, right? Please, at Usada Pekora's birthday festival, if you could tweet a lot about it, I'd be so happy, peko, so please, please, please tweet a lot!
まあ、なんでもうさだぺこらがこの昔の状態のぺこらだと、あ、でもこれもめちゃめちゃ可愛いぺこだけどね、でもみんなも多分気になっていると思う、一肌、一皮むけたうさだぺこらを見たいと、アップデートしたうさだぺこらを見たい？
Well, as for why Usada Pekora is in this old state as Pekora—ah, but this is also super cute Pekora, though! But I think everyone's probably curious: do you want to see a fresh, evolved Usada Pekora, an updated Usada Pekora?
どれ？見たい？
Which one? Do you want to see?
可愛いしかなくない？ありがとぺこな、おめでとう、あとれのじありがとう！
Isn't it nothing but cute? Thank you, peko-na. Congratulations, and thank you for the donations!
もうあとたくさんつぶやいて、もっともっともっともっと鳴らしてぺこな、あ、見たい！
Tweet a lot more, make it ring more and more, peko-na. Ah, you want to see?
それじゃあ仕方ないぺこだな。
Well, it can't be helped then, peko.
じゃあ、アップデートしたうさだぺこらをあの曲で披露したいと思うぺこだから、ちょっと準備してくるから待っててね、すぐぺこだから！
Well then, I want to debut the updated Usada Pekora with that song, so I'm going to go get ready, wait for me, I'll be right back, peko!
じゃね、ちょっと待ってて！
See ya, wait a second!
お化粧直しなきゃ！急げ急げ！
I gotta fix my makeup! Hurry, hurry!
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！ 作詞：畑 亜貴　作曲：俊龍
[Pekorandom Brain! - Lyrics: Aki Hata / Music: Shunryu]
なんだっけは？叫んじゃえは？
What was it? Just shout it out!
時間だ！毎日ヘーイ！
It's time! Every day, hey!
だってこの風だぞ笑えないじゃん笑え
Because with this wind, you can't help but laugh, right? Laugh!
てっこなんだんだ胸の中
[Teko nan dan dan] inside my chest,
てっこなんだんだ聞きたいとま
[Teko nan dan dan] want to hear it more,
のんだののんだのって主役が主役だヤッホー！
[Nonda no nonda no] the star is the star, yahoo!
のんだののんだのって主役が主役だ受け取り取り戻せるぞ
[Nonda no nonda no] the star is the star, you can take it back!
なんか意外になたたんご、たーたんご
Somehow unexpectedly [tatan go, tatan go]
ぴゅんとプロペラ回れ
Spin the propeller in a snap!
どこへ向かうさ不思議知らない知らないんだ
Where are we headed? It's mysterious, I don't know, I don't know!
なんと世界を繋ご繋ご
Connecting the world somehow, connecting it,
銀河越えたら銀河
Crossing the galaxy, the galaxy,
大切に思うんだ
I cherish it dearly.
そんなのどれもいいじゃいいじゃん
Any of that is fine, right?
退屈嫌だドラゴンの位置暮れま
Boredom is awful, dragon's position...
大事な場所なんてさ
Important places and such—
自分で作らなくちゃ
You have to make them yourself!
それぞ先輩がどらどらどらどらどうだ
Is that so? Senior, how is it, how is it, how is it?
ありがとうにはとか
To thank you, or something—
なんかんばいはびっくりだわ
Somehow it's surprising!
生きてりゃ毎日平和
If you're alive, every day is peaceful.
大もんだいのアトには楽しいことあるから
After big problems, fun things await!
なんちゃんぺいは叫んじゃえは
[Nanchamp ei wa] just shout it out,
時間だ！毎日ヘーイ！
It's time! Every day, hey!
だってこの風邪だぞ笑えないじゃん笑え
Because with this wind, you can't help but laugh, right? Laugh!
てっこなんだんだ胸の中
[Teko nan dan dan] inside my chest,
てっこなんだんだ聞きたいとま
[Teko nan dan dan] want to hear it more,
のんだののんだのって主役が主役だヤッホー！
[Nonda no nonda no] the star is the star, yahoo!
のんだののんだのって主役が主役だ受け取り取り戻せるぞ
[Nonda no nonda no] the star is the star, you can take it back!
そんな空でも君のすぐ行きたいのまわる
Even in such a sky, I want to go right to you, spinning around.
どちらがじめんとかしない染み出すな
Which one is the ground? Don't ooze out!
突破してる手柄もどうか
Breaking through, are those achievements any good?
なんもならない、誰が会いたいって言っているの？
It amounts to nothing—who is saying they want to meet?
らんだむぶれいん！
Random Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
叫んじゃえ わあっ
Shout it out, woah!
事件だ 毎日 タイヘン
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだ と
Saying it's the seed of great success...
笑え… 泣いちゃうな笑え！
Smile... Don't cry, smile!
ぺこらった るんるん らった
Pekoratta run run ratta,
ぺこらんだむしちゃいけため
Pekorandom should not be—
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
無視か yes か うりゃー
Ignore or yes, ugh!
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
ランダムだ random!!
It's random, random!!
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
無視か yes か うりゃー
Ignore or yes, ugh!
受取拒否れんぞ!
You can't refuse delivery!
なんと意外な touch and go
What an unexpected touch and go,
びゅんとプロペラまわれ
Propeller spinning zooming around!
どこへ向かうかは 知らない
Where we're heading, I don't know,
知らないんだもん
I don't even know!
なんと世界はつながっちゃう
Somehow the world gets connected,
ひょいと越えたら銀河系
Jump across and it's the galaxy!
誰に会いたいって思うんだろ?
Who is it I want to meet?
そんなのどうでも
Well, whatever about that,
いい じゃん いい じゃん
It's fine, it's fine!
退屈イヤだったらこっち来れば?
If you hate boredom, why not come over here?
大事な場所なんてさ
Precious places and such,
自分で作らなくちゃ
You've got to make them yourself,
これぞ説教だ!
Now that's a lecture!
どう だっ どう だっ どう だっ
How's that, how's that, how's that,
有り難た迷いか～
Grateful hesitation~?
らんだむぶれいん!
Random Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
びっくりだ わあっ
Surprised, woah!
生きてりゃ 毎日 タイヘン
Living means everyday is tough,
大問題の後には
But after major problems,
楽しいこと あるから
There are fun things waiting!
らんだむぶれいん!
Random Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
叫んじゃえ わあっ
Shout it out, woah!
事件だ 毎日 タイヘン
It's an incident, everyday is tough!
大成功のタネだ と
Saying it's the seed of great success...
笑え… 泣いちゃうな笑え！
Smile... Don't cry, smile!
ぺこらった るんるん らった
Pekoratta run run ratta,
ぺこらんだむしちゃいけないままで
Pekorandom should be kept as is!
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
無視か yes か うりゃー
Ignore or yes, ugh!
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
ランダムだ random!!
It's random, random!!
no no 脳の指令
No no, the brain's command,
無視か yes か うりゃー
Ignore or yes, ugh!
受取拒否れんぞ!
You can't refuse delivery!
どんな空でも here we go
No matter what sky, here we go,
くるっと機体がまいわる
The machine spins around!
どっちが地面とか 知らない
Which way is ground, I don't know,
知りたくない
I don't want to know!
どうかしてってるって 褒め言葉?
Is "you're crazy" a compliment?
どうにもならないよりましさ
It's better than being hopeless,
誰か会いたいって言ってよ!
Say you want to meet someone!
嬉しいからさね やっほー やっほー
Because I'm happy, yahoo, yahoo!
冒険選ぶならこっち来れ ば?
If you choose adventure, come over here?
まずは一歩目からだ
First, starting from step one,
千里はちょっとムリだろ!
A thousand miles is a bit impossible!
やばい 本音だ!
Oops, that's my true feeling!
まってっ まってっ まってっ
Wait, wait, wait,
思わず で じゃっ たよ～
It slipped right out~
ぺこらんだむぶれいん!
Random Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
こうなったら わあっ
Once it comes to this, woah!
メチャクチャやってみるか
Shall we try going totally wild?
みーんな！ つ、ついに…！ 見えちゃってる？ 見えちゃってるぺこか？
Everyone! Fin-, finally...! Can you see it? Can you see it, piko?
あ、やばい！ 見え…
Ah, oh no! Seen...
ぺこらの新しいお顔よ！
Pekora's new face!
どうぺこですか？ ぺこらの… 可愛くなったぺこかな？ どう？
How is it? Did Pekora... get cuter? How is it?
え、可愛くなった？
Eh, did I get cuter?
別人、ちょっと待ってよ。ちょっと、ちょっと誰よ！
A different person, wait a second. Wait, wait, who are you!
コメントでさ、別人じゃねえぺこなんじゃ、かわい、かわいそうのくせしてもちょっとね、あの、お化粧アップしただけいました。ちょっと見て、いくよ？
In the comments, saying "Isn't that a different person?", I just put on makeup. Look, here we go?
どんな顔になる、せーの、ぱっ！
What kind of face will it be? Ready, set, pop!
ああ！ せーの、ぱっ！
Ah! Ready, set, pop!
せーの、ぱっ！
Ready, set, pop!
どうぺこか、こんなね、表情も豊かになり、ちょ、髪の毛もちょっと、どうぺこですか、このさらさらな感じにもなってね、そして
How is it, with such rich expressions, my hair is silky too, and...
ぺこらのオリジナル曲、ぺこらんだむぶれいんを、このアップデートしたぺこらで歌わせて、そして踊っていただいたぺこ！
Pekora's original song, Pekorandom Brain, sung and danced by this updated Pekora!
大混雑も ダイスキ
Even massive crowds, I love it!
楽しいなら ダイスキ
If it's fun, I love it!
ぺこらんだむぶれいん!
Pekorandom Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
歌いちゃえ わあっ
Sing it out, woah!
マダマダやっちゃうかな
Shall we keep going even more?
大旋風吹き荒れろ
Let a great whirlwind blow!
笑え… 明日も笑え！
Smile... Smile tomorrow too!
ぺこらった るんるん らった
Pekoratta run run ratta,
ぺこらんだむしちゃいみたい
Pekorandom is like...
脳がなんか伝え たがると
The brain wants to convey something,
「変ワレ 変ワレ セカイ中」
"Change, change, throughout the world!"
じゃあ飛んじゃえ変えるために
Then let's fly to change things,
みんなみんな聞こえるかい?
Can everyone, everyone hear me?
らんだむぶれいん!
Random Brain!
わあっ
Woah!
びっくりだ わあっ
Surprised, woah!
生きてりゃ 毎日 タイヘン
Living means everyday is tough,
大問題の後には
But after major problems,
楽しいこと あるから
There are fun things waiting!
あれ？ あ、あれ？ ぺこらのご褒美、2021年12月都内某所。
Huh? H-huh? Pekora's reward: December 2021, somewhere in Tokyo.
綺麗なお姉さんが楽器を持っている。
A pretty lady is holding an instrument.
兎田ぺこら誕生日を祝うため…
To celebrate Usada Pekora's birthday...
あ、続々と人が来たぺこだよ。
Ah, people keep arriving one after another, piko.
何が起きるぺこなのだ？ 何が起きるの？
What's going to happen, piko? What's going to happen?
いや、ぺこら知ってるけど。知ってるぺこだけど、何が起きてるぺこなのだ？
Well, Pekora knows though. I know, but what on earth is happening?
一夜限りのセッション。
A one-night-only session.
ちょっと、ちょっとシュール。だけど、もしかしてぺこだけど、ぺこらの好きな
This is a bit surreal. But could it be, Pekora's favorite...
あの曲をやっ てくれるぺこなんじゃないの？
...aren't they going to play that song for me?
もしかして…、すごっ！
Could it be... amazing!
やばい、ちょっと、総勢39名。奏でる曲は？
Oh no, wait, a total of 39 people. What is the song they play?
あ、ぺこーらいた！ぺこーらいたねや！
Ah, Pekora's here! Pekora's here, you know!
うわー！まさか！ぺこーらのためだけの十曲来たー！
Whoa! No way! Ten tracks made just for Pekora are here!
今までゲームとかさ、サントラくんのバリエーションのさ、あれでさ、あの、大きにできたぺこだけど、
Up until now, with games and soundtrack variations, I've grown big, but...
一度もぺこーらのための十曲は聴いたことなかったぺこなの、だからまあ、ぺこら、うるさい、一度やめて、あれちょっと
I had never once heard ten songs made specifically for Pekora. That's why, Pekora—hey, shut up, stop for a second, um...
わかるよ！
I get it!
綺麗に一体で…あ、待ってぺこら！待ってなんか、こう、ずっと、今、ぺこらが！
Beautifully unified... Ah, wait, Pekora! Wait, what, like, right now, Pekora is—!
ぺこーらのためだけの十曲だよ、これは！こんな、ここに、ここはないぺこま！
These are ten songs made just for Pekora! There's no such thing as Pekoma here!
めっちゃ、めっちゃの心に響く
They resonate so, so deeply in my heart!
いやもう、もう、今日このまま死んでもいいかもしれないぐらい嬉しいぺこ！
I'm so happy I could practically die right here and now, Pekora!
しかもぺこーらの曲、この、乗ってるのってちょっと、なんか、あれなんだけど…ちょっとぺこら、静かに静かに！
And what's more, Pekora's song... riding on it is a bit, well... wait, Pekora, be quiet, be quiet!
いや、山をずーっと黙って聞いておこう、そうしようぺこ！
No, let's keep quiet and listen to the whole thing, let's do that, Pekora!
あ、トライアングルじゃん！ぺこらも、もう、できるかな、隣でやったら。
Ah, the triangle! I wonder if I can do it too, playing right next to them.
え、すご…もう胸がいっぱいすぎる…
Whoa, amazing... My heart is just too full...
みんな、この39名一人ひとりぺこらを想いながら吹いてくれたっていうこと、ぺこだよね。
Everyone, all 39 of you, playing while thinking of Pekora—that's what Pekora is all about.
後ろにあれ、カジノのね、やってるやつじゃん、なんか、ちょっと、空気読めぺこだよ、後ろ。
Back there, that's the casino thing, right? Read the room a bit back there, Pekora!
せめて、もうちょっとボス戦とかあってぺこだろ！
At least have some boss fights or something, Pekora!
え、まじか！こんな、こんな何度も聴きたいことぺこじゃん、こんな、ビデオがあるということは、
Seriously! I'd want to listen to something like this over and over again, Pekora. The fact that there's a video means...
聞きたいときにいつでも聞ける、
I can listen to it whenever I want to hear it!
この人たち上手いなあって…もう、あとで、あとで伝えるぺこだけど…当たり前だ！馬鹿野郎が！
These people are so good... I'll tell them later, but... Obviously! You idiots!
なんでやねん…
Why's that...
なんか、ぺこーら指揮者やりたい！今からでも想像できる。
I want to be the conductor, Pekora! I can imagine it even now.
ぺこーらがなんか指揮者やってるみたいで、めっちゃいいよ。しかも、今日の配属早めに、優しくね！
It feels like Pekora is conducting, it's so nice. Moreover, today's assignment is a bit early, be gentle!
やばい！やさしく…
Oh no! Gently...
終わりよ！
It's over!
ああ、いいよ！もっと、もっと！もっと！
Ah, nice! More, more! More!
ああ、もう、もう、最高、あり…
Ah, man, it's just the absolute best, thank...
ドラクエ×ぺこ～ら 去年は色々ありました。
Dragon Quest x Pekora: Last year had various things happen.
「ここはスライムレース場だよ、遊んでゆくかい？」
"This is the Slime Race track, want to play?"
待って！
Wait!
②スラりん！
#2 Slirin!
頑張れ！頑張れ！
Do your best! Do your best!
画面外に…画面外！！
Off-screen... Off-screen!!
寝るなよ！
Don't fall asleep!
あんた負けてる！
You're losing!
スリルを味わおうぜ、みんな！スリル！！
Let's taste the thrill, everyone! The thrill!!
ギャンブルに夢中になったり…一度待て！あ、ちょっとあの、コインが下がるような切り札、ちょっと見てくれる？
Getting absorbed in gambling... Wait a second! Ah, can you check if there's any trump card to lower the coins?
マジでいけよ！本気で行け！頼むぞ！
Go for real! Do it seriously! I'm begging you!
こんなカジノにハマってるアイドル、いや、ぺこだろ！誰も欲しくねえぺこだろ！
An idol hooked on a casino like this—no way, that's just Pekora! Nobody wants that, Pekora!
それに加え…売れねーの！？パパの形見、嘘じゃん！やめろ！
In addition to that... It won't sell?! Dad's memento, you're kidding! Stop it!
バカたれ！バカたれ！バカたれならやめろ、バカたれ！
"You fool! You fool! If you're a fool, stop it, you fool!"
バカたれ！
"You fool!"
ちょっと待ってよ。
"Wait a second."
テメェ！ビアンカに何しやがんだ！
"Bastard! What did you do to Bianca?!"
あんたペコらの仲間に入んな！
"Hey, don't join Pekora's party!"
やった！やった！やったー！
"Yay! Yay! Yay!"
チキショー！
"Damn it!"
やった！やった！やった！待って待って！仲間にする！
"Yay, yay, yay! Wait, wait! I'll make you my friend!"
ブラウン！お前がいてくれてよかったマジで！お前と仲間になれてよかった！
"Brown! I'm so glad you were here! I'm so glad I could be friends with you!"
ペコらがいてくれてよかった。
"I'm so glad Pekora was here."
ぺこらさん
"Pekora-san,"
お誕生日 おめでとう！
"Happy Birthday!"
レベル上がった、イェーイ！
"Leveled up, yay!"
本当にちょっと最後にレベル上がったペコなんだけど、
"My level went up right at the very end..."
いや凄くね？一応カジノペコで本当にありがとうございます。
"Seriously, isn't that amazing? Thanks to the casino, thank you so much."
さっきね、引いてくださった方々は国たち音楽院の方々で、
"The people who played earlier are from Kunitachi College of Music,"
いや本当にペコらのわがままに付き合っていただき本当にありがとうございます。とてつもなく嬉しくって、
"and thank you so much for putting up with Pekora's selfishness. I'm so incredibly happy,"
生きててよかったなって本当に思うペコです、マジで。
"I truly feel so glad to be alive, seriously."
最後レベルも上がったからね、今年もレベルアップしていきたいなと思うペコです。
"My level went up at the end too, so I hope to level up even more this year, peko."
そして、やばいね、ペコらもこんな、もう喜んでこれで終わりでいいやとか、そんなことじゃないペコだからね。
"And, oh man, Pekora's not the type to just be happy and think 'okay, that's it'."
みんながきっと待っているであろうコラボパート、行きたいペコですか？コラボパート。
"The collaboration part everyone is surely waiting for, do you want to go to it? The collab part."
どうよ？あんたたち、気になるペコたんじゃないの？コラボパート、行きたいっしょ？
"How about that? Aren't you guys curious, peko-tan? You want to go to the collab part, right?"
もうね、じゃあ早速行きましょうペコですか？コラボパートもね、たくさんたくさん、たくさんのペコらが、あの、お誘いした方々を呼んでいます。
"Alright then, shall we head right to it, peko? We've invited lots and lots of people Pekora invited for the collab part."
そして、あの、これはね、コラボパートも事前に収録してあるので、あの、安心してペコらもねちょっと今の気持ちをちょっとリセットできるようにね、でも凄く嬉しかったな、
"And, since the collab part was also pre-recorded, you can rest assured, so Pekora could reset her current feelings a bit, but I was so happy,"
ってのがあるからね。じゃあコラボパートへ、レッツゴー！
"so let's go to the collab part, let's go!"
Ah whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気マジック！
"Ah, town like a cake with whipped cream, suki! yuki! maji magic!"
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
"Confetti from the sky are angel wings celebrating the winter festival"
好き！雪！本気マジック！
"Suki! Yuki! Maji Magic!"
白銀の街へ 出かけるの Go Go Go
"We'll head to a silver snowy town, go go go"
雪の汽車が 街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
"A snow train runs through the town, choo choo choo"
絵本みたいな 景色を 君に見せてあげるから
"I will show you a landscape straight out of a picture book"
願い込め て呪文 さあ （さあ） 唱え て （さん はい）
"Make a wish, recite the charm, now (ready?), chant it (one, two, three, go!)"
abcd ドドシシララシシ マジカル ミラクル pop！
"ABCD do do shi shi la la shi shi magical miracle pop!"
Ah whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気マジック！
"Ah, town like a cake with whipped cream, suki! yuki! maji magic!"
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
"Confetti from the sky are angel wings celebrating the winter festival"
Light upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気マジック！
"The illuminated aurora-colored town, suki! yuki! maji magic!"
子どもでいられたら Dream Land
"If I could stay a child, dream land"
I hear that beat from town The cute angel will come down
This is my home I'll let you know Namara fantastic !
"This is my home, I'll let you know, namara fantastic!"
Lovin’ the sharp cold weather season love love love
"Lovin' the sharp cold weather season, love love love"
Wish in' the ice and magic won't melt whew whew whew
"Wishin' the ice and magic won't melt, whew whew whew"
Can’t we be like this forever ? wanna feel excited still
"Can't we be like this forever? Wanna feel excited still"
Imagine ( ready ? ) and recite the future ( here we go ! )
"Imagine (ready?) and recite the future (here we go!)"
1234 sui kin chi ka moku magical miracle pop !
"1234 sui kin chi ka moku, magical miracle pop!"
Ah feelin ' like a hopping rabbit , suki ! yuki ! maji magic
"Ah, feelin' like a hopping rabbit, suki! yuki! maji magic"
When the energy from the earth comes , we can live tomorrow like we want to
"When the energy from the earth comes, we can live tomorrow like we want to"
Wanna give the shiny snow white heart to you , suki ! yuki ! maji magic
"Wanna give the shiny snow white heart to you, suki! yuki! maji magic"
Don't think about trying to look like an adult !
"Don't think about trying to look like an adult!"
I hear that beat from town The cute angel will come down
Ah whip したケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気 magic
Ah, a town like a whipped-cream cake, I love it! Snow! Serious magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ woo
The confetti from the sky is the winter festival's celebrating angel wings, woo!
白銀の国へ出かけるの go go go
Heading out to a country of silver snow, go go go!
雪の列車が街を駆け choo choo choo
The snow train runs through the town, choo choo choo!
絵本みたいな景色を 君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a landscape straight out of a picture book.
願い込めて呪文 さあ （さあ） 歌え （さん はい）
Make a wish (ready?), recite a charm (here we go!)
abcd ドド シシ ララ シシ マジカル ミラクル クル pop！
abcd do do shi shi la la shi shi magical miracle pop!
Ah whip したケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気 magic
Ah, a town like a whipped-cream cake, I love it! Snow! Serious magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti from the sky is the winter festival's celebrating angel wings.
light up したオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気 magic
The illuminated aurora-colored town, I love it! Snow! Serious magic!
子供でいられたら dream land
Wish I could just be a child, dreamland.
ladies and gentlemen, welcome to snow miku！
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Snow Miku!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き love love love
Lovin' the sharp cold weather season, love love love!
アイスも魔法も溶けないように ヒューフューヒュー
Wishing the ice and magic won't melt, whew, whew, whew!
ずっとこのままじゃダメなのは やっぱりドキドキしたいな
Can't we be like this forever? Wanna feel excited still.
未来求め呪文 今 （なう） 歌え （さん はい）
Imagine (ready?) and recite the future (here we go!)
1234 水金地火木 マジカル ミラクル クル pop！
1234 mercury venus earth mars jupiter, magical miracle pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分 好き！雪！本気 magic
Ah, feelin' like a hopping rabbit, suki! yuki! maji magic!
さっきもここさ、ここのキメポーズでもフルグラが、フルグラがひどかったよね
Even just now, during the pose here, the Full Graphic... wait, Full Graphic was terrible.
難しいからね、もう、もうフルグラでもプルプルしちゃうよ
Because it's hard, even Full Graphic makes me all shaky.
いやでも本当に！スバル先輩一緒にて踊ってくれて
No, but seriously! Subaru-senpai, dancing together with me—
あ、ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます、ぺこら！
Ah, thank you very much! Thank you, Pekora!
こっちこそ呼んでくれてありがとう！すごい嬉しい！
No, thank you for inviting me! I'm so happy!
楽しかった、ぺこら本当に！
It was fun, Pekora, really!
ああ、え、なんか、ところでなんか、ずっと持ってことあるんだけどさ今日
Ah, um, by the way, there's something I've been wondering about today—
なんか、お前、変わった？
Did you... change something?
え？なんか、変わってます？ぺこら、なんか
Eh? Did I change? Pekora, like...
え、かわいい！なんだそのメスの顔！
Eh, cute! What is that girly face?!
メスって、おい！
"Girly," hey!
え、マジで、スバル先輩、ぺこらはもとから女の子ぺこなんですけど！
Wait, seriously Subaru-senpai, Pekora's been a girl from the start, you know!
いやいや、スバルの知ってるぺこらは、あ、てがちぇい！違う！
No no, the Pekora Subaru knows is... Ah, "tegach-ei"! No!
似てないぺこなんだけど！ぺこなのものまね！
That's nothing like Pekora! That's a terrible impersonation of Pekora!
言ってるじゃん！あ、てがちぇい！やるやん！って
You always say that! "Ah, tegach-ei! You can do it!"
いや、そんな！なんか、なんていうの、そんなこと怖い顔でさ
No, it's not like that! Like, what do you mean, with such a scary face—
あ、てがちいぺこだよ！お前、そんなの、あ、ちいって
Ah, "Tegachi-peko"! You, like, "Ah, chii"—
ちいさぺこでしょ！それは声のトーンを下げろって言ってること一緒じゃん！
"Chiisa-peko"! That's the exact same as telling me to lower my voice tone!
でもなんかすごい可愛くなったぺこら！本当ぺこ！
But Pekora got super cute today! Really, Peko!
え、じゃあ一緒にちょっとポーズ取らないぺこか？
Eh, then shall we strike a pose together?
え、いいの？取りましょうぺこ！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！
Eh, really? Let's take one, Peko! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
え、なかなかスバル先輩とツーショットってないぺこだから、みんなちょっとスクショのチャンスだのぺこな！
Eh, it's rare to get a two-shot with Subaru-senpai, so everyone, this is your screenshot chance, Peko!
ちゃっちゃっ、ちゃっちゃっ、ちゃっちゃっ、ちゃっちゃっ！
Cha-cha, cha-cha, cha-cha, cha-cha!
かわいい！にほん、かわいいぺこね本当に！でも、え、そんな
Cute! So, so cute, Peko, really! But, eh, like that—
ぺこらは本当にかわいくなった！
Pekora really became so cute!
そんな褒めたって何も出ないよ、今日は！何も出ないぺこですよ！
Praising me like that won't get you anything today! Nothing's coming out, Peko!
出ないの？出ないのちょっと待ってよ！ちょっと待ってよ！なんか出るとと思って褒めてるさぺこなの、ですか？
Won't you? Won't you? Wait a minute! Wait a minute! Are you praising me thinking something will come out, Peko?
まあ、ちょっとありますね、その説は。
Well, there is a bit of that theory.
いやマジでないの？逆じゃん！
No, seriously nothing? It's the reverse!
でもなんかこうやってスバル先輩と二人でコラボってなかなか無いぺこだから、本当に今日
But doing a collab just the two of us with Subaru-senpai is pretty rare, so really today—
なんか嬉しさもあり緊張もあり、なんか、また二人でなんかやりませんか？ゲームとかさ。
I have mixed feelings of happiness and nervousness, so why don't we do something together again? Like games or something.
え？しっちゃっていいの？
Eh? Is it okay if we do?
しちゃいましょうよ！
Let's do it!
やろっぺこ、やろっぺこ！そう、なんかく、コラボは
Let's do it, Peko, let's do it! Yeah, like collabs—
他人数が多かったぺこだから、2人が本当に…あ、たしかに。
Usually had a lot of people, so just the two of us is really... Ah, true.
ないけど、結構ペコスバなんかやってほしいっていう人もいるみたいぺこだからね。
But it seems there are people who want to see PekoSuba do stuff together, Peko.
じゃあどっちがね、ゲームの腕が上か見せつけてやりますか！
Then shall we show everyone whose gaming skills are better!
結局勝負にならんぺこなの？ぺこらだけやん！やろっ！あ、たしかに！
In the end, it's not even a competition? It's just Pekora! Let's do it! Ah, true!
やろうじゃねえぺこなんだよマジで！
Let's actually do it, Peko, seriously!
まあでもね、今日は本当にお誕生日おめでとうだよ！
Well, but today, happy birthday to you!
ありがとうぺこ！やばい、そろそろ夕日が沈む頃になるぺこらしいから、
Thank you, Peko! Oh no, it seems the sunset is approaching soon, so—
ともに一緒に、あの夕日に向かって、帰ろう！行くぞスバル先輩！
Let's head together towards that sunset! Let's go, Subaru-senpai!
えー！おっけー！なになになにこれ、なになにこの光景！
Eh?! Okay! What, what, what is this scenery?!
恋は混沌の隷也
Love is the slave of chaos!
誰だ?邪魔するな MY MY LOVE 浅き深き者共よ
Who's there? Don't interfere, MY MY LOVE, you shallow and deep ones!
誰だ?守り抜け MY MY LOVE 馬が蹴躓きもの共よ
Who's there? Protect it, MY MY LOVE, you stumbling fools!
理性がちぎれる瞬間に 限界みたいだよ
At the moment reason tears apart, it feels like the limit!
そうだ!邪魔するな BYE BYE LIFE 出でよ噛うもの共よ
That's right! Don't interfere, BYE BYE LIFE, come forth, devourers!
そうだ!諦めな BYE BYE LIFE おもち焼きしもの共よ
That's right! Give up, BYE BYE LIFE, you mochi-baking fools!
あの子欲しいよ あげない かごめかごめ宇宙式
I want that girl, I won't give her up, kagome kagome cosmic style!
そうだ!邪魔するな BYE BYE LIFE 出でよ噛うもの共よ
That's right! Don't interfere, BYE BYE LIFE, come forth, devourers!
そうだ!諦めな BYE BYE LIFE おもち焼きしもの共よ
That's right! Give up, BYE BYE LIFE, you mochi-baking fools!
這いよります! 火星のうねり!
Crawling with you! Martian swell!
誰だ? 邪魔するな MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Don't get in my way, MY MY LOVE,
浅き深き者共よ
you shallow and deep beings!
誰だ? 守り抜け MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Protect it, MY MY LOVE,
宇宙でサイムリイ
psychically out there in space!
奪いたいのが愛の本能さ!
Wanting to snatch it is the instinct of love!
待て待て (にゃー!)
Wait, wait! (Meow!)
恋は混沌の隷也 現れし私は誰?
Love is a slave to chaos! Who am I that has appeared?
恋は混沌の隷也 選ばれし君の神ですよ
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your chosen god!
恋は混沌の隷也 身悶えし君の神ですよ?
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your writhing god?
恋は混沌の隷也 選ばれし君の神ですよ?
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your chosen god?
ラブをクラフト戦いの中だけ
Crafting love only in the midst of battle,
とかなんとか言っても 本当はこんなにこんなに大好き!
no matter what I say, the truth is I love you so much!
這いよります! 火星のうねり!
Crawling with you! Martian swell!
暗躍するぜ OUR OUR HEART
Operating in the shadows, OUR OUR HEART!
押し付けろ OUR OUR HEART
Forcing it upon you, OUR OUR HEART!
認知が斜めの純愛
Pure love with a skewed perception,
略奪みたいね?
almost like pillaging, isn't it?
認知が歪んだ純愛
Pure love with a warped perception—
あなたは逃がさない!
you won't escape!
そうそうそうなんだ! 暗躍するぜ COME COME HELL
That's right! Operating in the shadows, COME COME HELL!
武者震い COME COME HELL
Trembling with excitement, COME COME HELL!
あの子食べます だめです
"I'll eat that girl" — "No you won't!"
花いちもんめ 宇宙へ
Hana ichimonme, off to space!
あの子食べます もぐもぐ
"I'll eat that girl" — nom nom!
すっぱいも甘いもバリエーション
Sour and sweet, all sorts of variations.
すぐすぐに来て来て来て!
Come, come, come right away!
変な未来のニャルホテプ
Nyarlathotep of a strange future,
困らせて神になれ!
tease them and become their god!
宇宙的恐怖はみみこみできないでしょ
Cosmic horror shouldn't be overlooked, right?
とかなんとか言っても 本当にやっぱりやっぱり大好き!
no matter what I say, I really, really love you!
這いよります! 火星のうねり!
Crawling with you! Martian swell!
誰だ? 邪魔するな MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Don't get in my way, MY MY LOVE!
浅き深き者共よ
You shallow and deep beings!
誰だ? 守り抜け MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Protect it, MY MY LOVE!
宇宙でサイムリイ
Psychically out there in space!
奪いたいのが愛の本能さ!
Wanting to snatch it is the instinct of love!
待て待て (にゃー!)
Wait, wait! (Meow!)
恋は混沌の隷也 現れし私は誰?
Love is a slave to chaos! Who am I that has appeared?
恋は混沌の隷也 選ばれし君の神ですよ
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your chosen god!
恋は混沌の隷也 身悶えし君の神ですよ?
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your writhing god?
恋は混沌の隷也 選ばれし君の神ですよ?
Love is a slave to chaos! I am your chosen god?
ラブをクラフト戦いの中だけ
Crafting love only in the midst of battle,
とかなんとか言っても 本当はこんなにこんなに大好き!
no matter what I say, the truth is I love you so much!
這いよります! 火星のうねり!
Crawling with you! Martian swell!
誰だ dare dare? 誰だ?
Who's there? Who is it?
暗躍するぜ OUR OUR HEART
Operating in the shadows, OUR OUR HEART!
押し付けろ OUR OUR HEART
Forcing it upon you, OUR OUR HEART!
認知が斜めの純愛
Pure love with a skewed perception,
略奪みたいね?
almost like pillaging, isn't it?
認知が歪んだ純愛
Pure love with a warped perception—
あなたは逃がさない!
you won't escape!
そうそうそうなんだ! 暗躍するぜ COME COME HELL
That's right! Operating in the shadows, COME COME HELL!
武者震い COME COME HELL
Trembling with excitement, COME COME HELL!
あの子食べます だめです
"I'll eat that girl" — "No you won't!"
花いちもんめ 宇宙へ
Hana ichimonme, off to space!
あの子食べます もぐもぐ
"I'll eat that girl" — nom nom!
すっぱいも甘いもバリエーション
Sour and sweet, all sorts of variations.
すぐすぐに来て来て来て!
Come, come, come right away!
変な未来のニャルホテプ
Nyarlathotep of a strange future,
困らせて神になれ!
tease them and become their god!
宇宙的恐怖はみみこみできないでしょ
Cosmic horror shouldn't be overlooked, right?
とかなんとか言っても 本当にやっぱりやっぱり大好き!
no matter what I say, I really, really love you!
這いよります! 火星のうねり!
Crawling with you! Martian swell!
誰だ? 邪魔するな MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Don't get in my way, MY MY LOVE!
浅き深き者共よ
You shallow and deep beings!
誰だ? 守り抜け MY MY LOVE
Who's there? Protect it, MY MY LOVE!
宇宙でサイムリイ
Psychically out there in space!
奪いたいのが愛の本能さ!
Wanting to snatch it is the instinct of love!
待て待て (にゃー!)
Wait, wait! (Meow!)
這いよります! じょあまた来週!
Crawling with you! Well then, see you next week!
えっ？何？何？
Huh? What? What?
戻ったの？
Did you go back?
えっ、待って！呼び方？
Wait, your way of addressing me?
戻ったの？
Did it go back?
いやだって、戻ったって…
No, I mean, you went back to...
何が？何が？
What? What?
心境の変化？
A change of heart?
コロさんって呼んでたじゃん。
You used to call me "Korone-san".
なんね？
Why is that?
あんなにさ、近くに来てたのにさ。
Even though you got so close before.
なんでそんな急に遠ざかるねん！
Why are you suddenly distancing yourself?!
あの頃も覚えてないぺこなの？
Do you not remember those times either, Peko?
覚えてるよ！
I remember!
初めてコロさんって呼んでくれたじゃん。
You called me "Korone-san" for the first time.
裏でもずっとコロさんって呼んでたのにさ！
Even behind the scenes, you always called me "Korone-san"!
いや、あの時ちょっと、みんなが「コロさん、コロさん」って言うから、ぺこながちょっと距離縮めようかなと思って。
Well, back then everyone was calling you "Korone-san", so I thought I'd try closing the distance a bit.
なのにさ、急にコラボで「コロさん」って呼び始めたらさ。
But then, when you suddenly started calling me "Korone-san" during the collab...
気になるじゃん、ぺこじゃん！
It makes you wonder, doesn't it, Peko?!
気になるぺこじゃん！
It makes you wonder, Peko!
いや、気になるけどさ！
I mean, I was curious, but!
気になるにしてもさ、ねえ？
Even if you were curious, you know?
いつからさ、「コロさん」って呼んで…
Since when did you start calling me "Korone-san"...
それは怖いぺこじゃん！
That's terrifying, Peko!
普通に、普通にさ、怖っ！
Normally, normally... so scary!
急にさ、呼び方を変えられたらさ、ちょっと…
If someone suddenly changes how they address you, it's a bit...
あ、そうなんだ、気にしてたんだね。ごめん、それちょっと気にしてたんだ。
Ah, is that so? You were worried about it. Sorry, you were worried about that.
そういうこと、ぺこ？
Is that how it is, Peko?
いいんだよ。
It's fine.
じゃあ、もうこれからは、こうやって面と向かって確認できたから、「コロ先輩」は封印しよう。
Well then, from now on, since we were able to confirm it face-to-face like this, let's seal away "Koro-senpai".
じゃあ…「コロさん」って言っていってこと、ぺこ？
Then... does that mean I can say "Korone-san", Peko?
「コロさん」だよ！
"Korone-san"!
じゃあ、封印のぎを…
Then, the sealing ritual...
封印のぎ？ちょっと待って、封印のぎって何？もう一生「コロ先輩」というワードは出さないように、ここでもう…
The sealing ritual? Wait, what's the sealing ritual? So that the word "Koro-senpai" is never uttered again...
景色。
The scenery.
そう。
Right.
じゃあ、待ってるから呼んで。
Well then, I'm waiting, so call me.
じゃあ、もう今年はもう、「コロ先輩」とは言わなくて…
Well then, this year I won't say "Koro-senpai" anymore...
コロさん！
Korone-san!
ぺこら！
Pekora!
なになに？
What, what?
なにぺこ！もう！じゃあ若いも…
What is it, Peko! Jeez! Well then, the young ones...
というわけで1枚撮りますか？
So, shall we take a picture?
あ、いいですね！
Ah, sounds good!
え、なにこれダサっ！
Eh, what's this? So uncool!
ダサくね？ぺこがいちゃった
Isn't it uncool? Peko messed up.
撮り直そう、大丈夫、ちょっと
Let's retake, it's fine, wait.
あの、ま顔の方がいいんじゃない？
Um, wouldn't a straight face be better?
あ、まがおにしよう、ぺこっか
Ah, let's do a straight face, Pekokka.
えっ？いえーい！
Eh? Yay!
あ、じゃあいいじゃん、じゃあ
Ah, that's good, then.
じゃあ、あの、これからももあるだろうから
Well, um, since there will probably be more...
これから！？じゃあ一緒に、行こうぺこらで
From now on!? Let's go together, Pekora!
あ、じゃあ準備して、せーの！
Ah, then get ready. Ready, go!
ぺこらー！
Pekora!
人が溢れた交差点を どこへ行く?
At an intersection full of people, where are you going?
(押し流され)
(Pushed along with the crowd)
似たような服を着て 似たような表情で
Wearing similar clothes with similar expressions...
群れの中に紛れるように 歩いている
Walking as if blending into the herd...
誰かと違うことに 何をためらうのだろう
What is it that makes us hesitate to be different?
先行く人が振り返り 列を乱すなと
The people ahead look back, telling us not to break the line
ルールを説くけど その目は死んでいる
Explaining the rules, but their eyes are dead.
君は君らしく生きて行く 自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live your life true to yourself.
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by the adults.
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If we give up like that from the start,
僕らは何のために生まれたのか?
what were we born for?
夢を見るときは 孤独にもなるよ
Sometimes dreaming can be a lonely path,
誰もいない道を進むんだ
but you must walk the road where no one else is.
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start just by gathering in crowds.
Yesでいいのか?
Is "Yes" really okay?
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent majority.
どこかの国の大統領が 言っていた
A president of some country once said...
声を上げない者たちは 賛成していると
That those who don't raise their voices are in agreement.
選べる事が大事なんだ 人に任せるな
Having a choice is what matters, don't leave it to others.
行動しなければNoと伝わらない
If you don't act, "No" won't be conveyed.
君は君らしくやりたい事をやるだけさ
Just be yourself and do what you want to do.
One of themに成り下がるな
Don't sink down to become just "one of them."
ここにいる人の数だけ 道はある
There are as many paths as there are people here.
自分の夢の方に歩けばいい
Just walk toward your own dreams.
見栄やプライドの 鎖につながれたような
Tied down by chains of vanity and pride,
つまらないおとなは置いていけ
leave those boring adults behind.
さあ未来はきみのためにある
Come on, the future is there for you.
Noと言いなよ!
Say no!
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent majority.
誰かのあとついてゆけば
If you follow someone else's lead,
傷つかないけど
you won't get hurt, but
その群れが総意だと ひと言にされる
that herd will be labeled as the consensus.
君は君らしく生きて行く 自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live your life true to yourself.
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by the adults.
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If we give up like that from the start,
僕らは何のために生まれたのか?
what were we born for?
夢を見るときは 孤独にもなるよ
Sometimes dreaming can be a lonely path,
誰もいない道を進むんだ
but you must walk the road where no one else is.
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start just by gathering in crowds.
Yesでいいのか?
Is "Yes" really okay?
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent majority.
誰かのあとついてゆけば
If you follow someone else's lead,
傷つかないけど
you won't get hurt, but
その群れが総意だと
that herd will be labeled
ひと言にされる
as the consensus.
君は君らしく生きて行く 自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live your life true to yourself.
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by the adults.
初めからそう諦めてしまったら
If we give up like that from the start,
僕らは何のために生まれたのか?
what were we born for?
夢を見るときは 孤独にもなるよ
Sometimes dreaming can be a lonely path,
誰もいない道を進むんだ
but you must walk the road where no one else is.
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start just by gathering in crowds.
Yesでいいのか?
Is "Yes" really okay?
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent majority.
われらは せーの ペットボトル！
We are, ready, pet bottles!
え、いみふきやな
Huh, what does that mean?
え、かっこいいポーズ
Eh, cool pose!
あ、じゅるんじゅるんにしてる
Ah, it's all liquidy and gooey.
瑠璃ちゃんはなんなの？
What's Ruri-chan's pose?
え、これかっこいいポーズ
Eh, this is a cool pose.
かわいいわちゃわちゃの……え、ペットボトルの形しないといけないぺこでしょ
Cute and messy... Wait, aren't we supposed to make pet bottle shapes?
え、ペットボトルの形ってどういうこと？ 同じペットボトルの形これこれ！
Huh, what do you mean by pet bottle shape? Just like this, like this!
え、これ？ え、これ、これがペットボトルでしょ？ いいじゃんいいじゃん！
Eh, this? This is a pet bottle, right? Awesome!
え、いみふくじゃん。ちょっとダサい、ダサいから。あ、かっこよくなくない？これ足上げたら。
That's weird. It's a bit lame. Isn't it uncool if you raise your leg like this?
これ足上げたらペットボトルポーズ、よし、あ、いいじゃん！
Raising your leg like this is the pet bottle pose! Yeah, nice!
え、いみふくじゃん、かわいい！
That's hilarious, so cute!
でさ、瑠璃ちゃんも今日、え、ダサくね？誰だ誰だ誰だ。
And Ruri-chan today—wait, isn't that lame? Who's that?
え、今日、今日、今日は？
Wait, today, today, what about today?
そうそう、今日さ、ペコちゃんさ、生誕祭に来てくれて本当に
That's right, thank you so much for coming to Pekora's birthday stream today!
ありがとうございます、ぺこらは！
Thank you so much, Pekora!
いやいやいや、どういたしまして！ めちゃくちゃかわいい！
No, no, not at all! It's super cute!
なんか、4人でさ、歌えたの、本当にぺこらはちょっとね、嬉しくて
I'm really so happy that the four of us could sing together today.
なんか、なんだかんださ、最近コラボとかもさ、ゆるゆるやってたりもしたぺこだからさ
We've been doing collabs casually lately too, so I'm really glad, peko.
なんか、うんうん、嬉しかったな、きょう。ありがとうございますほんとに！
Yeah, I'm so happy today. Thank you so much!
おーや、楽しかったね！ ねえ、楽しかった！
Man, that was fun! Hey, it was so fun!
なんか、なんか、いいな。楽しかったね、トワちゃん。
It feels so nice. Wasn't it fun, Towa-chan?
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
いいよいいよ、ぺこらのね、生誕祭だからさ。
It's fine, it's fine, it's Pekora's birthday after all.
なー、なー、なー。これ、これ、これ！
Hey, hey, hey! Look at this, this, this!
お互いの、乗っ取る気持ちでカメラの前にね。そうそうそう。
With the feeling of taking over each other's spot in front of the camera, right?
いや、乗っ取り、ぺこらの生誕祭にする。
Yeah, taking it over to make it Pekora's birthday stream.
なんか、わちゃわちゃがすごすぎね、ぺこが、マジで。
It's just too chaotic and fun, seriously, Peko.
なんでものなか、いい感じじゃない？ペットボトルっぽいよね。
Doesn't it feel like pet bottles?
ねえ、なんか、こういうわちゃわちゃがいいぺこだから、なんか、また集まりたいぺこだね。違うことでもな。
Hey, since this chaos is so Pekora-like, I want us to gather again for something else too.
本当？呼んでもらえるってこと？
Really? Does that mean you'll invite us?
やべ、人気者だテレビこ、みんなも呼んでぺこだよ。
Geez, I'm a popular TV star Peko! Everyone call for Peko too!
あれ、黙ってる？やばやばやば。
Huh, are you staying quiet? No, no, no!
いや、やだ、ぺこちゃん。い、やだなの、ペットボトルが嫌ななの。
No way, Pekora-chan. I don't like pet bottles!
トワちゃんが怖い。トワちゃんが一番怖い。
Towa-chan is scary. Towa-chan is the scariest!
なんでよ、圧を感じないでよ！迷子迷子ぺこじゃん。
Why, don't project such heavy pressure! We're totally lost Peko.
じゃあ、牡丹ちゃんペコラたち生配信に行こっかな？
Botan-chan, shall we go to Pekora's live broadcast?
ダメ！行きないで！
No! Don't go!
行きないで、行きないで！
Don't go, don't go!
ちょっと、ほら、せっかくさ、ペットボトルなんだからさ、もっと喋れんよ！
Look, since we're pet bottles, talk more!
もっと喋れんよ！
Talk more!
行くよ、みんなで何行きがう？
Let's go, where are we going together?
みんなで何行きがう？行こう！
Where are we going together? Let's go!
行きたい、行きい！あれ、ペコラまだライブある、ごめん。
I want to go! Wait, Pekora still has a live, sorry.
え？え、嘘でしょ？
Eh? Seriously?
うそだよ！
Just kidding!
想いの冒険を
Let's not forget our adventure of feelings,
忘れずに全部言えるかな
I wonder if I can tell you all of it without forgetting?
君から聞きたいよ
I want to hear it from you.
何回目の僕に出会った?
How many times have you met me?
僕は変わりました
I have changed,
新しい君に出会うために
In order to meet a new you.
久しぶりだねって
"It's been a while,"—
言えたならここで泣こうか
If I could say that, should I cry right here?
好きとかって 嫌いとかって
"I like you," "I hate you,"
何回だって愛を歌う君が
You singing of love over and over again
恋しくって 嘘じゃない本当だよ
I've grown to yearn for, it's true, no lies.
また出会おう
Let's meet again.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
Disliking our "II" and returning to "I",
何回だって間違ってきたよ
We've made mistakes so many times.
消せない後悔と 冷えない愛情が
Unerasable regrets and uncooling affection
恋を再起動する
Reboot our romance.
ほら“I”を嫌ってまた“II”に戻って
See, disliking "I" and returning to "II",
“III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
Let's become "III" and connect our love.
言いたい感情は 伝えたい正解は
The emotions I want to express, the correct answers I want to convey,
想いの冒険は これからもちゃんと続いていく
Our adventure of feelings will properly continue from here on.
想いの冒険は
Our adventure of feelings...
好きとかって 嫌いとかって
"I like you," "I hate you,"
何回だって愛を歌う君が
You singing of love over and over again
恋しくって 嘘じゃない本当だよ
I've grown to yearn for, it's true, no lies.
また出会おう
Let's meet again.
想いの冒険は…
Our adventure of feelings...
想いの冒険を 忘れずに全部言えるかな
I wonder if you could tell me the adventure of your feelings
君から聞きたいよ 何回めの僕に出会った?
I want to hear from you how many times we've met.
僕は変わりました 新しい君に出会うために
I've changed to meet the new you.
また出会おう
Let's meet again.
好きとかって 嫌いとかって
I love you, I hate you,
何回だって愛を歌う君が
You sing of love every time.
恋しくって 嘘じゃない本当だよ また出会おう
It's no lie, it's the truth, let's meet again.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
We hate II and go back to I,
何回だって 間違ってきたよ
Making mistakes over and over again.
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が 恋を再起動する
Endless regrets and uncooling passion restart love.
ほら“I”を嫌ってまた“II”に戻って “III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
We hate I and go back to II, becoming III to connect love.
言いたい感情は 伝えたい正解は
The feelings I want to say, the right answer I want to convey,
たったひとつだけ ありがとう
Is just one. Thank you.
恋して…バカ。
Fall in love... idiot.
愛にして…バカ。
Make me love... idiot.
バカでいい この先もずっとこのまま…バカ。
Idiots are fine, let's stay like this forever.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
We hate II and go back to I,
何回だって 間違ってきたよ
Making mistakes over and over again.
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が 恋を再起動する
Endless regrets and uncooling passion restart love.
ほら“I”を嫌ってまた“II”に戻って “III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
We hate I and go back to II, becoming III to connect love.
言いたい感情は 伝えたい正解は
The feelings I want to say, the right answer I want to convey,
たったひとつだけ ありがとう
Is just one. Thank you.
はぁ… はぁ… みなさーん…
Ah, everyone...
少しちょっと待ってもらいます…
Thank you so much for waiting.
みなさん どうぺこらにしたか?
Everyone, how did you like Pekora's...
合言葉すり そして
Catchphrases and collaboration parts,
コラボパートを 楽しんでいただけたぺこが 可愛すぎる!
Did you enjoy them? Pekora was too cute!
ありがとペこな。ありがとペこな。
Thank you, Pekona. Thank you, Pekona.
やでももう もう ライブも終盤
Well, the live is reaching its final stretch,
そして 今日は告知を3つ させていただきたいなと
and today I have three announcements to share with you!
思います。まずは ちょっと1つめの告知 行きたいなと
First, I'd like to announce...
思います!2つめは…こちら!じゃーん!
The second one is... Ta-da!
うさだぺこら 誕生日記念2022のグッズが 発売となります!いえーい!
Usada Pekora's 2022 Birthday Commemoration Goods are now on sale! Yay!
こちらね フルセット ございまして
We have a full set available here,
そして フルセットのね 購入特典には
and the full set purchase bonus includes...
なんとなんとなんとなんと メルセージやサインが入った あの ゆきはぐれ先生の かきおろしポストカードが
A handwritten postcard message from Hagure-sensei!
ついております こちらね かわいいぺこ メッセージが届いてからね あの お楽しみにということで
It comes with the cute Pekora message, so please look forward to it!
けどけど ちょっとフルセット買えないよ ちょっとごっさいがって人のために
However, if you can't buy the full set because it's a bit pricey,
単品も ご用意してございます!
individual items are also available!
それが こちら!じゃーん!まずはひとつめは アクリルジオラマスタンド!
First is the Acrylic Diorama Stand.
そして こちらなんと ラバーマット&カードスリーブ イラストは さいとーはなお先生ぺこです!
And second, the Rubber Mat & Card Sleeves! Illustrated by Saito Hanao-sensei.
そして もうひとつが こちら!
And finally, the third item...
And the last item...
欲しい！1家に1台は欲しいと思いますペコですので、
I want one! I think everyone should have one in their home,
ぜひぜひぜひお買い求めしていただけたらなと思います。
so please, please, please consider getting one!
そして今回のグッズペコなんですけども、大変申し訳ございません！
And regarding the merch this time... I'm terribly sorry!
ちょっとね、ペコラの不手際で、ええとこちらのグッズ販売、日本の方は10時、この配信が終わったあとにすぐ買えるペコなんですけど、
Due to some missteps on Pekora's part, um, for the merchandise sales here, people in Japan can buy it right at 10:00, right after this stream ends,
海外にキルペコが海外ツー、アイムソリ、ソーリー！
but for those overseas, overseas too, I'm so, so sorry!
で海外にキルの方は10時10分、あの日本時間の10時10分、あの10分ちょっと遅れちゃうわけ、でも安心！
for those overseas, it's 10:10, 10:10 Japan time, it'll be about 10 minutes late, but don't worry!
全員買えるペコですから、あの限定の商品など一切ございません！
Because everyone can get it, there are absolutely no limited items!
買いたい方は全員買えますので、安心してね。ちょっと10分遅れちゃって申し訳ないペコだけど、安心して買えますので、
Everyone who wants to buy can buy, so rest assured. I'm sorry it'll be about 10 minutes late, but you can buy it safely,
ぜひともぜひともお買い求めしていただけたらなと思います。
so please, please consider purchasing it.
そして告知2つ目は、こちら本日10時半から、えっと、アンコールメンバー限定のライブがございます！
And the second announcement is this! Today at 10:30, um, we have an encore member-only live!
こちらね、メンバー限定のアンコールライブが10時半から行いたいと思いますので、ぜひぜひ、あのメンバーの方そして今からね、入って下さる方も楽しんでいただけたらなと思いますペコですので、
Here, we'll be holding the member-only encore live starting at 10:30, so I hope members, and those joining from now on, will enjoy it, Pekora, so
よろしくお願いいたしますとがんばるペコですので、よろペコなと。
please take care of me, I'll do my best Pekora, so Yoropeko.
あ、よかったくれてにぞいぺこな。
Ah, good, right? Zoipeko.
そして、多分別番のが一番みんな楽しみにしてくれたのかな。
And maybe the last one was what everyone was looking forward to the most.
告知3つ目、ちょっといぺこですか？ナイト！嘘だペコラ！踊りゃく、2曲目をリリース決定！
Third announcement, is it a little Ipeko? Night! No, Pekorain! Decided to release the 2nd song, Odoryaku!
その名も！言い訳バニー！ええええこのあとみんな聴きたいぺこですか？これ聴きたいぺこですか？
Entitled! 'Excuse Bunny'! Eeeh, does everyone want to listen after this? Do you want to listen to this?
聞ききたい？こちらもね、あの、ま、このあとあの、お披露目もしたいぺこなですけども、24時、本日の24時に、あの配信も開始されるので、ぜひとも皆さんたくさん聴いていただけたらなと思います！
Want to hear it? Here too, um, well, after this, um, I'd like to unveil it too, but at 24:00, at 24:00 today, the stream will also start, so I really hope everyone listens to it a lot!
それじゃ、そろそろ新曲言ってもいいぺこですか？
Well then, can I finally talk about the new song?
いい？いいぺこですよね。
Good? It's good, right?
聞きたい？わけてや、それじゃ、いっちゃいますか？新曲、言い訳バニー！
Want to hear it? Separate ya, well then, shall we go? The new song, 'Excuse Bunny'!
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
なんとかなんないのかな
Can't something be done about it?
涙 隣のあいつじゃまだな
Tears, that guy next door is still...
行くない！そんなこと！
No way! Such a thing!
ダメ！ダメ！ダメ！
No, no, no!
全力疾走中！
Running at full speed!
戸惑いは違うの！
Confusion is different!
競争 日に日に募るの
Competition, growing day by day,
なんの寂しい 気持ち？気持ち？
What kind of lonely feeling? Feeling?
全身写真で ペッパレットスケルトン
Full-body photo with a palette skeleton
あんな子に負けない どこだって全力疾走！
I won't lose to a girl like that, full speed everywhere!
行くなり！振り返り！
Going? Looking back!
しています！
I am!
いいわけなんて わかってる
Excuses... I know,
あてもない こうでもない 夢に見ましょう
aimless, not like this, let's dream in our dreams
突き抜け My my my my...
Break through, My my my my...
聞ききたくない いいわけバニー じんだんだのユートピア
Don't want to hear it, excuse bunny, stomping Utopia
じんだんだんだん
Stomping, stomping
緑 緑 緑 緑まきの おもしろトッピング
Green, green, green, green-rolled funny topping
どっちが好きなのよ
Which one do you like?
ダメ！ダメ！ダメ！ よそ見しないで！
No, no, no! Don't look away!
ダメ！ダメ！ダメ！ 萌え剥ぎ出したいのわ
No, no, no! I want to rip out my moe!
私の方でしょ？
It's me, right?
時雨線 反対方向 ワンセグ
Shigure line, opposite direction, one-seg
いいわけバニー
Excuse bunny
大都会は大得意？
Are you great at big cities?
興味がねーから超ニガテ
Not interested, so I'm super bad at it
一歩引いて見守るはるかに 届くできごみ
Stepping back, watching far away, reaching events
きっと私並み 暴れてそれに
Surely like me, rampaging and then
毎回エイリアン 絡むちゃっかりトライアル
Every time alien, getting entangled sneaky trial
全身あるのみ 暴れてそれに
All-out only, rampaging and then
説得だ！あんたたち！やっつけまいさい！
Persuasion! You guys! Go get 'em!
疲れちゃったひと休み
Got tired, a short break
なんとかね やってよね
Managed somehow, do it
明日の私 任せたの
Tomorrow's me, I leave it to you
My my my my...
決められない いいわけバニー
Can't decide, excuse bunny
うやむやげしき アンコールそそくさ
Vague scenery, encore hastily
ににににににがちな はなしかはま
Nininininini-tending to be talking hammer
落としもえ いいわけバニー
Dropping moe, excuse bunny
あんたしまいです そんなのってないわ
You're done for, there's no such thing
私一筋の 本命でしょ？
I'm your one and only true choice, right?
マイウェイ 逃がさない
My way, won't let you escape
どこへだって行けばいい
Where should I go from here?
言い訳ないよ しないよょうがないじゃない
There's no excuse, no reason not to!
すすけろ my my my mind
Keep running through, my my my mind!
聞きたくない！言いわけバニー
I don't want to hear it, you excuse bunny!
地団駄no！優柔不断だんだんさ
Stop dragging your feet, you're so indecisive!
ハニーバニーだりーだりーんだーさ
Honey, bunny, tired, tired!
マジな話 どっち（どっち？）が好きなの！
Seriously, which, which one do you like?!
（ダメダメダメ）よそ見しないで
(No, no, no!) Don't look away!
（ダメダメダメ）もう逃げ出したいのは私のほう
(No, no, no!) I'm the one who wants to escape!
（でしょでしょ？）通しません！反対方向
(Right, right?) No way! Dead end!
wanted！言いわけバニー
Wanted! Excuse bunny!
前進あるのみトラブルってエネミー
We must move forward, trouble is the enemy!
wanted！言いわけバニー
Wanted! Excuse bunny!
ぶつけろ my my my mind
Collide with my my my mind!
聞きたくない！言いわけバニー
I don't want to hear it, you excuse bunny!
そばにいて いいわけバニー
Stay right by my side, excuse bunny!